welcome back to another shotcut tutorial
欢迎回到另一个截图教程
in this video we'll be working with
在这段视频中 我们将使用
multiple audio tracks we're gonna add
我们将添加多首音频曲目
music to a video and we're going to look
音乐到视频中 我们要看一看
at the audio filters and effects in shot
在镜头中的音频滤镜和效果
cut so to get started I'm going to open
切开 开始吧 我要打开
a file and I'm going to open up just
一份文件 我要打开
this that's an mp3 music file so I'll
这是一个MP3音乐文件 所以我会
open that up and we see it appears here
打开它 我们看到它出现在这里
it starts playing its gonna follow the
它开始播放它将跟随着
same rules as if it were a video clip so
同样的规则 就像它是一段视频剪辑一样
we can jump to a certain part hit the
我们可以跳到某一部分点击
spacebar to play or we can control here
空格键来玩 或者我们可以在这里控制
and play it and we can go reverse go to
然后播放它 我们可以反向转到
the beginning if we drag this down to
如果我们把这件事拖到
our timeline it'll appear and it comes
我们的时间表 它会出现 它会到来
on as a video track v1 so we can play it
作为视频曲目v1播放 这样我们就可以播放它
here and now we're watching it in the
此时此刻 我们都在看着它
video track as opposed to our source but
视频跟踪 而不是我们的来源 但是
what we really want is an audio track
我们真正想要的是一首音轨
here so we could leave it in in the
这里 这样我们就可以把它放在
video track it's just gonna play as a
视频曲目 它只是作为一个播放
video with a black background whatever
带有黑色背景的视频
the our settings are I think 1920 by
我想我们的背景是1920年前
1080 but if we click on filters here or
1080 但如果我们点击此处的过滤器或
like we learned in the last video we can
就像我们在上一段视频中学到的那样 我们可以
also click filters up here it does the
此外 在此处单击Filters 它会执行
same thing it just brings up the filters
同样的事情 它只是带来了过滤器
tab and then it says what is selected is
选项卡 然后它会显示所选内容是
this Bach concerto in D for two violins
这首巴赫D大调双小提琴协奏曲
D minor and it's selected in red and so
D小调 用红色选择 所以
we can zoom out and kind of see this
我们可以缩小图像 可以看到这一点
selection so anything we apply will
选择 因此我们应用的任何内容都将
happen to this entire selection which is
发生在整个选择上 这是
the entire audio so I'll just click this
整个音频 所以我只需点击这个
plus and if we click on audio it'll show
另外 如果我们点击音频 它将显示
us different audio effects so we have
我们有不同的音效 所以我们有
fade in and fade out of the audio we
淡入和淡出我们的音频
have gain and volume which is I use
有收益和体量是我用的
quite a bit to increase or decrease the
增加或减少相当多的
volume of a clip balance and pan are
夹子天平和平底盘的体积是
going to be for like right and left so
就像是向右和向左一样
let's click on just to show you I'll
让我们点击一下 向你展示我将
click on this gain volume 1 and the
点击此增益卷1 然后
option we have here is just level so
我们这里的选择就是水平 所以
it's just a single level if we hit play
如果我们按下Play 这只是一个关卡
we can look over here in this audio peak
我们可以在这个音频峰值中看到这里
meter and we can kind of see what this
我们可以看到这是什么
is doing here so this is the volume
是这样的 所以这是音量
right now if we adjust it lower the
现在如果我们把它调低
volume gets softer and we can see over
音量变得更柔和 我们可以看到
here it's you know down to negative 40
在这里 你知道 降到了负40
50 decibels if we go up above 0 it'll
50分贝如果我们调到0以上
get louder and if we go too high it's
再大声一点 如果我们开得太高
gonna get red
会变红的
and kind of clip out at certain points
并在某些点上剪下
so we want to avoid that read whenever
所以我们希望在任何时候避免这种读取
adjusting audio okay well I want to show
调整音频好的 我想展示一下
you though so this is on the video track
你以为这是录像带上的吗
so suppose we did want to bring in some
那么假设我们确实想要引入一些
video too we can go open file we can
视频也可以 我们可以打开文件
find some video here so I'll just do
在这里找到一些视频 所以我会做
this go to this clip right here so this
这个就是这个夹子 所以这个
clip already has some audio associated
剪辑已有一些关联的音频
with it if I were to bring it down right
带着它 如果我把它降下来
now
现在
it would overwrite whatever portion this
它将覆盖这一部分
white portion it would actually
白色部分 它实际上会
overwrite the audio we could also do if
在以下情况下也可以覆盖音频
we check this little icon here this
我们在这里选中这个小图标
ripple trim and drop what it will do now
涟漪修剪 放下它现在要做的事情
it changes from overwrite to insert so
它从覆盖更改为插入 因此
what this will actually do is break the
这实际上将打破
audio so we'll come in the very
音频 所以我们将在非常
beginning we'll play the audio here and
一开始 我们将在这里播放音频
what it'll do if I were to take that oh
如果我拿着它 它会做什么哦
now I lost my video see it's not in the
现在我把我的录像带弄丢了 看 它不在
playlist because all I did was open that
因为我所做的就是打开播放列表
so we have to reopen the video again and
所以我们必须重新打开视频
I drag it down pause we drag it down
我把它拖下去 停顿一下 我们把它拖下去
we're gonna point to insert this video
我们将指向插入这段视频
so now the video is inserted here
所以现在视频被插入到这里
meaning it'll play the video and then
这意味着它将播放视频 然后
pick up right where I left off and so
从我停下来的地方重新开始 所以
it's not actually over it didn't
它实际上并没有结束 它没有结束
overwrite the audio if that makes sense
如果有意义 则覆盖音频
anyway what we can actually do if we
不管怎么说 我们实际上能做的是
don't want to have it on the same track
我不想让它在同一条赛道上
which we don't really that's not ideal
我们真的不知道 这不是很理想
we want to be able to play the waterfall
我们想要能够玩瀑布
and have the music playing in the
把音乐放在房间里
background
背景
so we need a separate audio track to do
所以我们需要一个单独的音轨来做
that we click these three lines here and
我们点击这三条线
we go add audio track now we have an A
现在我们要添加音轨了 我们有了A
one A one down here and V one here so
一个A一在这里 V一在这里 所以
that a is the audio track and the V is
A是音轨 V是
the video so we see the video has an
这个视频 所以我们看到这个视频有一个
option for turning on and off the video
打开和关闭视频的选项
turning on and off the sound this lock
打开和关闭这把锁的声音
icon just locks the track and keeps it
图标只是锁定曲目并保留它
so we can't edit it at all but that down
所以我们根本不能编辑它 只能把它删掉
here on the audio track it has an option
在音轨上 它有一个选项
for turning off the audio and locking
用于关闭音频和锁定
but there's no picture because the video
但没有照片 因为视频
track only has audio with it so then
曲目只有音频 所以
we'll have to open up because I'm not
我们必须敞开心扉 因为我不是
using this play the playlist I probably
使用这部剧播放列表 我可能
should do that if we go open file we
如果我们打开文件我们应该这么做
have to go back to our audio file
必须返回到我们的音频文件
and bring it in here we can drag it to
把它带到这里 我们可以把它拖到
the playlist and then we won't keep
播放列表 然后我们就不会
losing it every time and then we also
每次都失去它 然后我们也
drag it down to our audio track so we
把它拖到我们的音轨上 这样我们
put it down here in the audio track it's
把它放在音轨里 它是
to the very beginning and now we'll just
从一开始 现在我们只想
click this and hit delete and that
点击这个 点击删除 然后点击那个
deleted that just that part of the audio
只删除了音频的那部分
will click this first part and hit all
将点击此第一部分并点击全部
that the this one here this is the
这个就是这个就是这个
ripple delete so it deletes and sucks it
涟漪删除 这样它就会删除并吸走它
back to the beginning and now we'll have
回到开始 现在我们将有
both the waterfall and the music playing
无论是瀑布还是音乐
because the video has its own audio
因为视频有自己的音频
track and the audio is on a separate
音轨和音频在单独的
track from the video so we have two
视频中的曲目 所以我们有两个
audio sources and one video source
音频源和一个视频源
playing and maybe if we find so this
玩耍 也许如果我们发现是这样的话
audio down here doesn't have the effects
这里的音频没有效果
we applied to it if we click on filters
如果我们点击过滤器 我们就会应用它
we see there's no effect because that
我们看到没有影响 因为
effect we applied was up here on this
我们在这上面应用了效果
other one that we deleted so we'd have
另一个我们删除了 这样我们就有了
to reapply this it sounds like the
要重新应用这一点 听起来像是
waterfall is a little bit too noisy so
瀑布有点太吵了 所以
we can actually click this plus and add
我们实际上可以点击这个加号并添加
in this gain volume to the audio of see
在这个增音量中看到的音频
what's selected just the video clip so
只选择了视频剪辑的是什么
we'll turn that down and now that the we
我们会拒绝的 现在我们
should hear the music a lot more than
我应该更多地听到这首歌
than the audio then the audio from the
先是音频 然后是来自
waterfall
瀑布
[Music]
[音乐]
that's kind of cool and then we can add
这很酷 然后我们可以添加
in other ones too we can do like
在其他地方 我们也可以这样做
balances gonna be left and right if it
余额将是左和右 如果
comes out of the left speaker or the
从左边的扬声器或
right speaker we can add in fade in so
右扬声器 我们可以添加淡入 所以
if we hadn't fade in it kind of you can
如果我们没有淡出你能做到的那样
see we'll zoom in here a little bit so
看 我们会把这里放大一点 所以
this little black triangle can be
这个黑色的小三角形可以是
adjusted right now it's doing about a
现在调整后 它的速度大约是
one-second fade I think so we didn't
一秒钟的褪色 我想我们没有
hardly notice that one but let's do a
几乎没有注意到这一点 但让我们来做一个
fade out that when we will notice so
淡出 当我们注意到的时候
we'll add a fade out and now we'll hear
我们将添加淡入淡出 现在我们将听到
this sort of fade out to the music oh
这种感觉随着音乐逐渐淡出哦
[Music]
[音乐]
I'm sorry I'm applying it to the
我很抱歉我把它用在了
waterfall
瀑布
nothing nothing music no wonder listen
没什么没什么音乐难怪要听
let's come over here I'm gonna cut the
我们到这边来吧 我要把
music to the end of this so we'll click
音乐结束 所以我们将点击
here to split and I'll go to the second
在这里分开 我会去第二个
having to delete so now while I have the
我现在不得不删除它 而我有
audio track selected you see a mistake
选择音频曲目 您会看到错误
that you'll probably make too but I make
你可能也会做 但我会做
it quite often so I apply the effect to
这很常见 所以我将这种效果应用于
the wrong clip we see I did a fade in
我们看到的错误片段我做了淡入
and fade out to the waterfall and not to
消失在瀑布中 而不是
the music so now that the music selected
音乐 所以现在音乐选择
I'll add in the fade in and I'll add in
我会加入淡入度 我会加入
the fade out so now we have a fade in
淡出所以现在我们有淡入
and fade out applied to both of our
淡出适用于我们两个人
Clips we actually don't even need them
我们实际上根本不需要夹子
on the waterfall one so I'm just gonna
在瀑布一号上 所以我只想
get rid of them on here and now we'll
在这里除掉他们 现在我们就
play this so you hear that the audio
播放这个 这样你就能听到音频
fades in and then the idea of audio
淡入 然后是音频的想法
fades out so that's kind of cool
淡出 所以这是一种酷
not a whole lot of audio effects here we
我们这里没有太多的音效
have what's this one Pass
这张通行证是什么？
so this is gonna be like I don't even
所以这就像我甚至不知道
know but there's some different options
我知道 但有一些不同的选择
here if you know audio and you know what
如果你知道音频 你知道吗？
you want to do I do a lot of my audio in
你想做我做了很多我的音频在
audacity so if I have to do too much
所以如果我不得不做太多的事
crazy stuff I'll actually edit it
疯狂的东西 我真的会编辑它
outside in audacity and then I'll bring
大胆地在外面 然后我会带上
it in once it's all once I have the
它在一次它是所有的一旦我有
things to apply to it that I want anyway
适用于它的东西 我无论如何都想要的
that's working with effects and filters
就是使用特效和滤镜
for audio in shot cut and also how to
有关快照剪辑中的音频以及如何
work with multiple tracks and we can add
使用多首曲目 我们可以添加
in if we want we can add in another
如果我们愿意的话 我们可以再加一个
audio track and then we have another one
音轨 然后我们有另一个
we can add in a video track and we'll
我们可以添加视频曲目 然后
talk more about that to working with a
更多地谈论这一点与
lot of different tracks here but if ever
这里有很多不同的曲目 但如果有的话
you get a lot going on you can always
你有很多事情要做 你总是可以
click here and go to make track shorter
单击此处并将曲目缩短
then we can see all of all the tracks we
然后我们就可以看到我们所有的痕迹
have going on we can also adjust this if
如果发生了什么 我们也可以调整这个
we want to see more of what's happening
我们想了解更多正在发生的事情
in our tracks and less of what's
在我们的足迹中 而不是什么
happening up here so yeah go ahead and
发生在这里所以是的 继续吧
leave your questions or comments below
在下面留下您的问题或评论
if you have any questions about working
如果您对工作有任何疑问
with audio with the filters or audio
带有过滤器或音频的音频
tracks in shotcut and I hope to see you
Shotcut中的痕迹 我希望见到你
in the next video
在下一个视频中